<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Statistical Computing 2 Portfolio</title>
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Statistical Computing 2 Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to HPC</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-hpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-hpc/</guid>
      <description>High performance computing is a way to process data much faster than a single computer possibly could. This is achieved by parallelizing code across a cluster of computer and nodes.
Logging in Setting VPN (if not on university premises) If you are not on university premises you will have to set up the University VPN. Setting up a connection on Linux can be done as follows:
Go to https://uobnet2.bristol.ac.uk and sign in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Linux</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-linux/</guid>
      <description>Linux is a open-source version of the UNIX operating system.
 Kernel: heart of the operating system and manages everything from memory to hardware devices. Shell: interface between the user and the kernel. There are different types of shells, for example Bourne shell (sh) and Bourne Again Shell (bash) etc.  Users First of all, since linux is a multiuser system, we might want to check the following:
 who you are logged in as using whoami who else is logged in: users or who for more details   File management All the data is organized into files and directories, all of which are organized into a tree structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>